You know I said that the beginning of my last work,
在我上一本书的开头,
Carl Gustav Jung had said that
卡尔 · 荣格曾经说过，
running through each life like a thread is
像一根线贯穿每一个人生命的，
a question that you've come to answer
是一个你要回答的问题，
and you're lucky to find it.
你很幸运地找到了它。
And that the question is more important
而且这个问题
than the answer by far.
比答案要重要得多。
So for me, a span certainly for the last 40 years,
所以对我来说，在过去的40年里,
how do we be fully present to our world
我们如何在一个痛苦和
at a time when the suffering and the prospects
有意识的生命形式的前景如此黯淡的时候，
for conscious life forms are so grim.
把我们完全呈现给世界。
How do we look straight into the face of our time
我们如何直视我们的时代，
which is the biggest gift we can give
这是我们能给予我们所处时代
to be present to our time.
的最大礼物。
It's so tempting to
想像乌龟一样
want to just pull back like a turtle inside its shell,
缩回壳里是很诱人的,
it's so tempting to want it just part of it,
想只成为它的一部分也是很诱人的,
close your eyes and busy yourself with other things.
闭上眼睛，忙自己的事情。
So how do we do that?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
How do we be with our world without going crazy?
我们如何与我们的世界相处而不至于发疯呢？
I think that's been the question that is
我想这就是我一直追寻的问题，
pursued me and I'm actually grateful for it,
当发现了这样的问题时，
when you find a question like that.
我对此心怀感激。
It's good news.
这是个好消息。
乔安娜 · 梅西和大转折
万物互联
We're seeing it this time just when we're ready,
我们在这个时候看到，就在我们准备好的时候，
you know, we have the capacity now
你知道，我们现在有能力
to blow ourselves to bits and then setting in.
把自己炸成碎片然后再开始。
Huge impact on the society.
这对我们的社会产生了巨大影响。
We're also seeing that there is this immense
我们还看到，在每一个独立的人身上，
mystery and beauty in every separate one,
都存在着这种巨大的神秘和美丽，
you look into the eyes of any being,
看着任何生命的眼睛,
human or non-human, you can sort of see.
不管是不是人类，你都可以看到，
oh, we're in this great mystery.
哦，我们生活在这个大谜团中。
We go back to the teachings in the Buddhist tradition
我们回到佛教传统中对我来说
that are very meaningful to me.
非常有意义的教义。
Central to that way of perceiving the world,
这种感知世界的方式的核心,
just as it is central to, ah, systems thinking
正如它是系统思维的核心一样，
is the apprehension that everything is connected.
即对万物互联的领悟。
We're just like our American mystic environmentalist
我们就像美国神秘主义环保人士
John Muir said,
约翰·缪尔所说的,
you can pick up any piece
你可以拿起这个世界
of this world, stone, the twig without finding it
任何一块石头或树枝，
hitched to everything else in creation.
而不会发现它不与创造中的其它一切相连。
This is so strong, this recognition of our interdependence,
这种对我们相互依赖的认识是如此强烈,
this arises that arises, this seizes that seizes,
此有故彼有，此灭故彼灭,
this comes to be that comes to be.
此生故彼生。
So I get teaching for our time,
我得到了我们这个时代的教导,
there's no private salvation.
即没有所谓私人的救赎。
I can't be who I am without you being or you are,
没有你或你的存在，我就不能成为我自己；
I can't be safe unless you're safe,
你不安全，我就不安全；
I can't be healed unless you heal,
除非你治愈，否则我无法治愈；
I don't have a final so separate little refuge I can go
我没有一个最终的独自的避难所，
to be redeemed and leave you out.
在其中我可以得到救赎而却把你排除在外。
This is amazing.
这真是太神奇了！
And I can look at you and see within you
我可以看着你，
the whole story
从你身上看到整个故事，
just as you and your mother's womb,
就像你和你母亲的子宫一样,
remember the whole journey of life evolving.
记载着生命的整个演化进程。
我们怎么会陷入这种困境？
What I see as
在我看来，
really propelling at this moment
此刻真正推动
this collective insanity of wasting our world
浪费我们世界的这种集体疯狂，
is actually our economic system our political economy,
实际上是我们的经济体系以及政治经济,
which thanks to the phrase of Norwegian deep-ecologist Sigmund Kvaloy
这要归功于挪威深层生态学家西格蒙德.克瓦洛的一句话,
I too call the Industrial Growth Society.
我也称之为工业增长社会。
Behind it it has the power of industry and its
在它的背后是工业的力量
mighty technologies and organization,
和它强大的技术和组织,
but the truly operative work is growth.
但真正在背后驱动的是增长。
This is a political economy
这是一种政治经济，
that sets its goals and measures its success
它以增长的速度来
in how fast it can grow.
设定目标并衡量其成功与否。
Growing what?
增长什么呢？
Wisdom？
增长智慧？
Health？
增进健康？
Longevity？ Creativity？
延长寿命？ 提升创造力？
One thing only. Alas! One thing only.
只关注一件事。 唉！ 只关注一件事。
Profits.
利润！
The living systems of earth are coming apart
在工业增长社会的冲击下，
under the onslaught of the industrial growth society,
地球的生命系统正在分崩离析,
scrambling for the last dollars.
争夺最后一点钱。
So it's been several decades now that we have known
几十年来，我们已经知道
that we have been taking raw materials
我们从地球上提取原材料的速度
out of the body of earth faster than they can be renewed,
超过了它们更新和再生的速度,
people feel this,
你不必是个经济学家，
you don't have to be an economist，
都会有这种感觉，
I mean even a third grader can see that
我的意思是，即使是三年级的孩子也能看出来，
it can't keep growing in a limited world
在一个有限的世界里是无法继续增长的，
but somehow grown people walking around on two legs
但不知何故，用两条腿走路的成年人，
particularly if they're running for office,
特别是当他们在竞选公职时,
if they acknowledge that you can't keep going,
如果他们承认增长不能继续下去的话,
boo, you're a voice of gloom and doom,
卟，那是一个阴郁而绝望的声音，
and nobody wants to listen to you,
没人愿意听你的。
So there's this kind of charade,
所以就有了这样一种骗局，
ah, growth mania that keeps us stupid.
增长的狂热让我们一直愚蠢。
应对这个时代的痛苦
We are going through a hard passage in the journey of humanity in planet Earth.
在地球上的人类历程中，我们正在经历一个艰难的旅程，
This is a mammoth adventure.
这是一次巨大的冒险。
But in every myth, legend, adventure story
但是在我们的文化所珍视和传承的
of that our culture has treasured and passed on
每一个神话、传说和冒险故事中，
the hero and heroine is called at some point to look straight
男主人公和女主人公在某个时刻被召唤
into the face of the monster or I think the dosser
去直视怪物的脸，
and that turn to stone.
而不是心如死灰。
And we see it as a journey in which
我们把其视为一段旅程，
we are through our suffering with our world we are seeing
在这段旅程中，我们与世界一起经历苦难，
the immensity of the life in us.
我们看到了生命的无限。
Saint Francis for example the saint of ecology and christianity,
比如圣方济，生态学和基督教的圣人,
he didn't run from the bad news of his time,
他没有逃避他那个时代的坏消息,
he walked with Lady Poverty,
他与贫穷女士同行,
he kissed the leper,
他亲吻麻风病人,
he kept his eyes open to the devastation of war
作为战俘，他对战争带来的破坏
and as a prisoner of war.
保持着清醒的认识。
And by, uhm, being with that pain collected with his brothers and sisters,
他与他的兄弟姐妹们一起承受痛苦,
he could sing the Canticle of the Sun
他唱《太阳颂》这首歌，
and open to the blessedness and holiness of life
向生命的幸福和神圣敞开心扉
and get a sense of, una immensitas vitae, the immensity of life.
并感受到生命的瀚海无边。
We need each other for this,
为此，我们需要彼此，
we need each other in ways I think that we never have before
我认为我们需要彼此的方式是以前从来没有过的，
because all through human history
因为在整个人类历史上，
there was this tacit assumption
都有这样一种默认的假设，
that life would continue on this planet.
即生命会在这个星球上继续存在。
Oh yeah, there were wars,
哦，是的，有战争,
there was poverty, there was playing in pestilence
有贫穷，有瘟疫，
death of course,
当然还有死亡,
an illness and old age and all of that,
疾病和衰老等等,
but always there was that tacit assumption
但是总有这个默认的假设，
that life would continue.
那就是生命会继续下去。
And that the work of our hands and hearts would go on
我们的双手和心灵的工作会
for future generations and that's what's lost now.
为子孙后代继续下去，而这些东西我们现在正在失去。
And that loss of certainty for the ongoingness of life
我认为，对生命的持续性失去确定性
is the pivotal psychological reality of our time I believe.
是我们这个时代的关键心理现实。
So my way of dealing with the overwhelm
因此，我应对这种不知所措事情的方法
is to look as straight in the eye and say there you are again
是直视自己的内心，然后说，你又来了，
to realize that we are suffering with our world.
意识到我们正在与我们的世界一起受苦。
And I try to pave it over and I'd apologize for it
我试着把它铺平，我会为此道歉，
and not see it as a personal weakness, a personal craziness,
不把它看成事个人的软弱、个人的疯狂
promise to bow to it and say ah,
答应向它鞠躬，并说，啊,
you are suffering with your world,
你正在和你的世界一起受苦,
it's the most natural thing in the world,
这是世界上最自然的事情,
most wholesome, healthy thing in the world too.
也是世界上最健康的事情。
Don't be afraid of your heartbreaking open,
不要害怕碎开你的心,
the heart that breaks open can hold the whole universe,
碎开的心可以容纳整个宇宙,
it's that big.
它是那么广大无边。
I want so much to feel sure.
我很想有确定的感觉。
I want to be able to tell people don't worry,
我希望能够告诉大家不要担心,
it's gonna be okay.
一起都会好起来的。
And you know what I realize that that would
你知道吗，我意识到这
not be doing anybody a favor.
并不能帮任何人的忙。
First of all， we can't know
首先，我们无法知道。
But secondly, if somehow we could be given a pill
但其次，如果以某种方式给我们一个药丸，
to be convinced don't worry, it's going to turn out okay,
让我们无须担心，一切都会转好的,
would that elicit from us our greatest creativity and courage?
这会激发我们最大的创造力和勇气吗？
No.
不会的！
It's that knife-edge of uncertainty
正是在这种不确定性的刀刃上，
where we come alive to our truest power.
我们才会发挥出我们最真实的力量。
So we do ourselves the favor.
所以我们要帮自己一个忙。
We honor ourselves to live with sufficient realism and dignity
我们尊重自己，以足够的现实主义和尊严来生活，
to know we're right with that knife edge of uncertainty.
知道我们正处在不确定性的刀刃上。
And we don't know how it's gonna come out,
我们不知道结果会怎样,
they're no guarantees.
没有任何保证。
Now I realize, oh wait
现在我意识到,
there aren't any guarantees anyway,
无论如何都没有任何保证。
they're no guarantees when you fall in love
当你坠入爱河时，
that you're gonna have a lasting relationship,
不能保证你会有一段持久的感情；
they're no guarantees when you
当你进入产房时，
go into labor that you're gonna have a healthy delivery,
不能保证你会有一个健康的分娩；
there are no guarantees when you put seeds in the soil
当你把种子种在土壤里，
that they'll be sufficient rain and warmth for a bumper crop,
不能保证会有充足的雨水和温暖来获得丰收。
There never has been guarantee for human life
人类的生命从来就没有保证，
and it's in that uncertainty and
正是在这种不确定性中，
this is like a exquisite wind and fire of uncertainty
这就像是一种精巧的风和火的不确定性，
that is the nature of life.
这是生命的本质。
All the wise, wise men tell us that.
所有聪明的智者都告诉我们这一点。
That's where we come alive.
这就是我们活着的地方。
在旧外壳中建立新世界
And now we see that this system is becoming
现在我们看到，
ever more fragile and as this system is beginning to crumble
这个系统变得越来越脆弱，而且这个系统开始崩溃。
and just, ah,  look at the mortgage crisis,
只要看看抵押贷款危机,
look at our ecosystems,
看看我们的生态系统,
look at our farm systems.
看看我们的农业系统。
Just as that is being less and less responsive to human needs,
就在这个系统对人类需求的响应越来越少的时候,
there's something quite wonderful happening.
有一些非常奇妙的事情发生了。
And that is the people are proceeding to build the new
那就是人们正着手在旧的外壳中
within the shell of the old.
建造新世界。
There are new ways emerging
新的方式正在出现，
and people are realizing more and more
人们越来越认识到，
that we can meet our needs without destroying our world.
我们可以满足我们的需要而不会破坏我们的世界。
Now that sounds pretty bland but actually that's revolutionary
这听起来很平淡，但实际上这是革命性的，
because if you take seriously
因为如果你认真对待
what proponents of the system are saying,
这个系统的支持者所说的话,
they're telling us
他们告诉我们，
that the only way we're going to be able to survive
我们能够生存的唯一方法，
is through permanent war and destruction of our environment.
就是通过永久的战争和对我们环境的破坏。
That's bullshit.
简直是胡说八道！
We've come for millions of years
我们来到这里已经有几百万年的历史，
and certainly thousands of years of recorded history,
当然还有几千年的历史记录,
these in great monuments of learning and art and culture, science.
这些都是学术、艺术、文化和科学的伟大丰碑。
And we were learning how to care we learned how to care.
我们学习如何关心并学会了如何关心。
Our ancestors passed that knowledge onto us.
我们的祖先把这些知识传给了我们。
第三次革命
We are so wonderful to be alive at this time
我们在这个时代活着是如此美妙，
when there is something taking place,
因为有一些事情正在发生，
there is a revolution taking place.
有一场革命正在发生。
And you're not going to learn about it by watching
你不可能通过观看主流公司
the mainstream corporate control press and television,
控制的新闻和电视来了解它,
but it is mammoth
但它是巨大的，
and I feel that we need so acutely to be aware of the dimensions
我觉得我们需要如此敏锐地意识到
of unfolding what's emerging in our time.
我们这个时代正在发生的事情的维度。
It is this what we call many of us the great turning
这就是我们许多人所说的大转折，
is the transition
即
from the industrial Growth Society to a Life- sustaining Society
从工业增长社会变成了生命可持续社会，
because we're seeing
因为我们看到，
that what we have been living in allegiance to and dependence upon
我们一直效忠和依赖的东西
is wrecking ourselves and our world,
正在毁灭我们自己和这个世界,
is robbing us of the future.
正在夺走我们的未来。
So I see it as the third revolution of our human journey.
所以我认为这是人类旅程中的第三次革命。
So 10,000 years ago back in the late neolithic,
在一万年前新石器时代晚期,
we settled down began to grow crops, produced the surplus
我们定居下来，开始种植作物，生产了盈余，
built walls on land, learned to write,
在土地上建设城墙，学习了写作,
learned to trade, built greeneries, built temples
学会了贸易，建造了绿地，建造了庙宇。
And this was this agricultural revolution that it took centuries.
这就是农业革命，它花了几个世纪。
And then the next revolution of comparable magnitude
下一次类似规模的革命
was just 300 years ago,
发生在300年前,
started in England with the steam engine
始于英国的蒸汽机、
and the mills and the mines and cheap energy
磨坊、矿山、廉价能源
and it is the industrial revolution.
以及工业革命。
And that affected how we view ourselves, our value,
这影响了我们如何看待自己以及我们的价值观,
how we relate to each other,
我们如何相互联系,
how we understand the living earth.
我们如何理解有生命的地球。
It began to bring to us the motion that the earth is
它开始向我们提出这样一个动议:
stockpile of resources to be extracted or
地球是有待开采的资源存储地，或者
a sewer for our waste to be pumped in.
为我们排放垃圾的下水管道。
It damned the world for us.
它为我们诅咒了这个世界。
And pitted us against each other
竞争的尖锐化
and in a sharpening of competition and
使我们彼此对立，
then desperation to get what we need based on a zero sum game.
并不顾一切地想从零和博弈中得到我们需要的东西。
And right on the heels of that
紧随其后的是
with all the obvious comforts and powers that it brought
它带来的显而易见的舒适和权力，
which we've become quite dependent on.
我们已经变得相当依赖它们了。
I don't want to sneeze at that
我不想对此嗤之以鼻，
but that's out of control now,
但现在已经失控了,
it's a runaway system.
这是一个失控的系统。
So now is emerging a fundamental change
因此，现在出现了一个根本性的变化，
that many see is the third revolution of our time,
许多人认为这是我们这个时代的第三次革命,
Lester Brown of earth policy institute calls it the ecological revolution.
地球政策研究所的莱斯特·布朗称之为生态革命。
And more and more of us are simply calling it the great turning,
我们越来越多的人简单地称之为大转折,
because that's what it seems to us as we
因为这就是我们所看到的，
think more and more about the future ones,
当我们越来越多地思考未来的时候，
as this we see ourselves approaching greater and greater breakdown,
当我们看到自己正走向越来越严重的崩溃时,
what will be left for the future ones.
会给未来的人留下什么东西。
And that question begins to hammer it our heart
这个问题开始敲打我们的心，
and as we think about them
当我们想到他们时，
and as they begin to inspire us
当他们开始启发我们
to work and to love this life
去工作，去爱生命，
to pass on to them so they'll be
并将其传递给他们，
air for them to breathe and water for them to drink
这样他们就会有空气可供呼吸，有水可供饮用
and soil for them to cultivate
以及有土地可供耕种，
that we imagine they'll look back at us,
我们可以想象他们会回头看着我们,
living in these early years of the third millennium
生活在第三个千年早期的
and say, oh, those ancestors,
那些祖先们,
they were taking part in the great turning.
他们正在参与大转折。
And while it's just as big and scope
虽然它和农业革命和工业革命
as the agricultural and the industrial revolution,
的规模和范围一样大,
it has to happen a lot faster,
但它必须发生得更快,
everyone agrees on this,
每个人都会同意这一点,
it has to unfold and just a matter of years.
它必须展开，只需要几年时间。
The good news is that it is, it is.
好消息是，确实如此。
Paul Hawken calls it blessed unrest,
保罗·霍肯称之为神圣的不安,
he calls it the greatest largest social movement in human history,
他称之为人类历史上最大的社会运动,
he calls it the movement with no name,
他称之为没有名字的运动,
it doesn't matter what you call it,
不管你怎么称呼它,
but it is our great good fortune
但是我们能活着是我们巨大的幸运，
to be alive now where we can put our wits
我们可以把我们的智慧和力量
and our strength and everything we ever learned
以及我们曾经学到的关于
about courage and interconnectedness to use.
勇气和相互联系的一切都用上。
大转折的三个维度
Sometimes I think
有时候我觉得
the work I do in the workshops is what I most want
我在工作坊里做的工作就是我最想要的，
is to give you player spectacles,
就是给你玩家意识,
so they and me and maybe I need to see it,
所以他们和我，也许我需要(通过玩家意识来)看看,
well you can see it.
你也可以看看。
And I think it helps to look for it in three
我认为从三个领域或者三个维度
arenas or dimensions of the great turning.
来寻找大转折是有帮助的。
The most visible perhaps
也许是最引人注目的，
and what we have been accustomed to calling
也是我们习惯于称之为和平正义
activism for peace justice or the environment,
或环境的行动主义,
those are all the actions to slow down the destruction
这些都是减缓工业增长社会
of the industrial growth society,
的破坏的行动,
that's all the political legal legislative regulatory efforts.
这就是所有的政治法律立法监管的努力。
It's the direct actions
这是直接行动，
and they're all aimed at buying us time
它们都旨在通过减缓破坏速度
by slowing down the rate of destruction.
来为我们争取时间。
That dimension is hard
这个维度很困难，
because you have as many defeats as victories
因为有许多的失败和胜利，
wears you out.
让你疲惫不堪，
burn out rate is a high
倦怠率很高，
but it's very important because it saves some lives
但这非常重要，因为它能拯救一些生命，
and it saves some species
拯救了一些物种，
and save some ecosystems and some of the gene pool
拯救一些生态系统和一些基因库，
for the society to come.
以供未来社会使用。
But it's not enough for the great turning
但是，即使这一切都成功了，
even if everything were just succeed.
对大转折来说仍是不够的。
Because the great turning this life-sustaining society
因为这个生命可持续社会的伟大转折
needs structures, ways of doing things,
需要结构，需要做事的方式，
rules of patterns of collective behavior,
需要集体行为模式的规则,
in ways of
需要在各个层面
construing our relations with each other at every level.
上构筑我们彼此之间的关系。
And that's happening,
而这正在发生,
that's that second dimension.
这就是第二维度。
第二个维度：可持续的结构
I think of that as like green shoots coming through the
我认为这就像是从一个功能失调的文明
rebel of a dysfunctional civilization.
的反叛者身上发出的绿芽。
There are new ways of holding land, land trust conservancies,
有新的持有土地和土地信托保护的方式,
new ways of growing and producing the food,
新的种植以及生产食物的方式,
permaculture, biodynamic farming.
朴门农业，生物动力农业。
I say no but some of them very old. We captured again.
我说没有，但他们中的一些非常古老，我们再次俘虏,
New ways of building, new forms of currency,
新的建设方式，新的货币形式,
new ways of measuring wealth and prosperity,
衡量财富和繁荣的新方法,
sustainability indicators rather than gross domestic product,
可持续性指标而不是国内生产总值,
new forms of healing, again ancient ones,
新的治疗形式，当然还有古老传统的方式,
new and old ways of teaching,
新式的和传统的教学方式,
new forms of renewable energy,
新形式的可再生能源,
such incredible ingenuity at work.
这些令人难以置信的聪明才智在发挥着作用。
It is astonishing.
这是令人惊讶的！
I love it that Paul Hawken is looking at those calls it
我喜欢保罗·霍肯在他的书中
in his book an immune response on the part of Earth
把它称之为地球上的免疫反应，
that life itself wants to go on and
生命本身想要继续下去，
this just what once you get on that sort of wavelength
一旦你超过了某种阈值，
then you too participate in this tidal change of creativity.
那么你也参与到了这个创造力的大变革中。
But these in ways of doing things will shrivel up and die,
但是这些做事的方式将会枯萎和消亡,
they won't last unless they're deeply rooted.
除非它们根深蒂固，否则它们不会长久。
And the way we see reality our values our understandings
我们看待现实的方式，我们的价值观，我们的理解，
and so that's the third dimension of the great turning,
这就是大转折的第三个维度,
a shift in consciousness,
意识的转变,
a change in our perceptions of reality.
我们对现实的认知的变化。
And that is astonishing.
这是令人惊讶的。
How vast that is right in our lifetimes.
这在我们有生之年是多么的巨大。
Scientists I know systems thinkers
我知道的科学家，像肯尼斯.博尔丁、格雷戈里.贝特森
like Kenneth Boulding, Gregory Bateson you know pioneers
这样的系统思想家，他们是先驱者，
they say,
他们说,
this is the biggest bite out of The Tree of Knowledge
这是人类5000年来知识树上
in 5000 years,
最大的组成部分,
because it's a basic cognitive revolution.
因为这是一场基本的认知革命。
What is that at root?
其根本是什么？
It's a recognition that our planet is a living system.
它是对我们的星球是一个生命系统的认识。
It's not just a sewer and a warehouse to be despoiled,
它不只是一个垃圾场和一个可以被掠夺的仓库,
and we belong to it
我们属于它，
like cells in a living body.
就像活体中的细胞一样。
It's a shift from seeing reality in terms of
这是一种从物质、事物和实体的角度
stuff and things and entities
来看待现实
to seeing it in terms of flows of relationship,
转变到从关系的流动以及
self regulating self evolving
自我调节和自我进化的角度来看待现实,
that can flower through time
这种转变会随着时间的演进
into patterns of extraordinary complexity and intelligence.
变成极其复杂和智能的模式。
I love the way that you can for example in these,
我喜欢这样的方式, 例如，
three dimensions enter at any point
你可以从任意的切入点进入这三个维度，
because they're mutually reinforcing.
因为它们是相互强化的。
You might decide that you're going to
你可能会决定你要做
do a holding action to save one tree
一个减缓破坏的行动来拯救一棵树，
like Julia Butterfly Hill for example
例如像茱莉亚.伯特弗莱.希尔（美国环保运动人士）一样
and that you'll go up for two weeks to sit in it,
花两个星期住到（加州红木上）,
you end up going up for over two years,
最后在上面住了两年多,
and changing the mindsets of hundreds of thousands of young people
通过使用手机来广播(思想)
through using your cell phone in the radio.
改变成千上万年轻人的心智。
Or you can decide to save one
或者你也可以决定
piece of the old-growth forest of ... land
拯救一块...原始森林的土地
like my colleage John Seed of the rainforest information center.
就像我的同事，热带雨林信息中心的约翰.赛德一样。
And he stood there
他站在那里，
standing there with his back to the trees
站在森林里背对着树，
while the logging, illegal logging was going around
到处都是伐木和非法伐木，
and the police were there to arrest the protesters
警察在那里逮捕抗议者，
and there was the screaming of the chainsaws and
空气中充斥着电锯刺耳的吱吱声
shouts of the police of their bullhorns
警察的喊声和喇叭声，
and the revving of the paddy wagon engines.
还有囚車引擎的转动声。
Just like that he had this epiphany that changed his life.
这时约翰有了顿悟，进而改变了他的人生。
He realized he wasn't
他意识到他不是
John Seed protecting the rainforest that he was,
保护热带雨林的约翰·斯德,
in essence the rainforest protecting yourself
本质上是热带雨林在
through this piece of humanity it had cradled into existence.
通过它孕育而生的这部分人类来保护你自己。
That experience is being repeated
这种经历我一次又一次地看到，
hundreds of thousands of times I've seen it again and again,
被重复了成千上万次，
as people acting in defense of life,
当人们为捍卫生命而行动的时候，
wake up to the grandeur of who they really are
他们觉悟到自己真正是谁，
and find sources of strength,
并找到力量的源泉,
synergies grace, beyond what they could have expected.
完全超出他们预期的协同效应。
That's the great turning.
这就是大转折。